Yovin Ransika Yahathugoda

Flat 303, Talbot Studios, 118 Talbot Street, Nottingham, NG1 5GP, United Kingdom Mobile: +44 7932614336 | Email: yovin.yahathugoda@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile - https://www.linkedin.com/in/yovin-yahathugoda/ | Digital Portfolio - https://www.yovinyahathugoda.com/

Kaggle Profile - https://github.com/yoviny/Deep-learning-Competitions

Profile

A confident and organised MSc Data Science student with experience as a Research Engineer in computer vision. I am passionate about Data Science, with practical experience in Data Science competitions through Kaggle. My strong analytical skills and adaptable quality have enabled me to work with multidisciplinary teams cohesively and achieve targets.

Professional experience

Self-Employed, Sri Lanka

20/12/2019 - 19/08/2021

Freelance Computer Vision Engineer

- Full-time Kaggle participant involved in Data Science and Deep Learning competitions in areas such as medical imaging and Optical Character recognition (OCR). A selection of completed projects is showcased in my digital portfolio.
- Developed a visual based fabric width inspection system as a prototype for a textile manufacturer in Sri Lanka.

John Keells Research (A division of John Keells Holdings PLC), Sri Lanka

02/04/2018 - 30/11/2019

Research Engineer

- Devised an imaging system capable of capturing images in multiple wavelengths by developing the electronic design and program code.
- Analysed Multispectral images using image processing techniques to obtain hidden details of the target object.
- Developed a drone based on open-source hardware to match unique requirements of the research project.
- Designed PCBs using Eagle PCB and performed circuit simulations in OrCAD.
- Reduced 3D print failures up to **40%** by upgrading existing 3D printer with new hardware and re-programming based on open-source firmware.
- Overcame software and electronic related errors in projects at JKR by troubleshooting and debugging.
- Performing prior art searches related to the research project.
- Participated in team discussions focused on developing novel ideas with a market potential.

Sri Lanka Ports Authority, Colombo, Sri Lanka

07/11/2016 - 29/01/2017

Engineering Intern - (Part of the industrial training required for the undergraduate degree)

- Diagnosing faulty networks inside the Colombo Port and supervising network cable repair jobs.
- Upgraded communication line between Engine room and control room of a Tugboat.
- Designed a system to monitor room temperature of Telephone Exchange and sound an alarm when temperature exceeds a certain level.

Education

MSc Data Science 09/2021- Ongoing

Nottingham Trent University, UK

Received a 25% scholarship and additional £3,000 bursary for previous academic performance.

Key modules: Software Engineering, Statistical Data Analysis and Visualisation, Applied AI and Data Mining, Deriving Business Value from Data Analytics, and Fundamentals of Big Data and its Infrastructure.

BEng (Hons) Electronic Engineering - 1st Class Honours (74.31%)

09/2014 - 01/2018

Sheffield Hallam University, UK

• Thesis title: Navigation System to Assist the Visually Impaired using Stereo Vision and Audio Feedback - This included Computer Vision and Machine Learning using Python, OpenCV and LIBSVM.

Core Competencies

Programming - Python, C, C#, C++ (Intermediate level), OpenCV, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Pandas, R, Linux Software – Eagle PCB, OrCAD, Matlab, Arduino, Visual Studio, Microsoft Office Suite Languages – English (Fluent) & Sinhala (Native)

Transferrable skills

- **Communication** Successfully defending presentations during external investor meetings at John Keells Research and during presentations throughout undergraduate and postgraduate studies.
- **Time management** Committed to meeting deadlines and achieving weekly objectives in multiple projects by prioritising workloads while working as a Research Engineer.
- **Leadership** Organised workshops and events while serving as the President of Aeronautical Club in Secondary School. Managing team members in undergraduate group projects as group leader to ensure all work is completed. Served as batch representative in the final year of undergraduate studies.
- **Project management** Identified and procured equipment and components required for the research project at John Keells Research.
- **Problem Solving/Critical Thinking** Providing solutions to problems faced while working on novel research projects and meet strict deadlines while working at John Keells Research.

Memberships

Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) – Member (MIET) Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) - Member

2018 - Present

2016 - Present

Certifications

Azure Data Fundamentals – Microsoft	14/01/2022
Big Data Specialisation - University of California San Diego	03/05/2020
<u>Deep Learning Specialisation</u> - By Andrew Ng	08/01/2020
<u>DL0101EN: Deep Learning Fundamentals with Keras</u> - IBM	30/11/2019
PH125.8x: Data Science: Machine Learning - HarvardX	27/11/2019

Interests & Achievements

AI/Deep Learning competitions

Ranked in the top 3% (59th out of 2059 participants) of the <u>Bengali handwritten classification</u> challenge hosted on Kaggle.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Volunteering John Keells Foundation (CSR), Buddhist Society of Lyceum International School Nugegoda
- President of Aeronautical Club at Lyceum International School Nugegoda.
- Shortlisted in two categories in the <u>Astronomy Photographer of Year 2021</u> competition hosted by Royal Museums Greenwich, UK. Nominated for the People's Choice Award in the same competition.

References

References available upon request